<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Bruno]]></title>
  <link href="http://blebon.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blebon.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-25T15:19:07+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://blebon.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Bruno]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Take Your Privacy Back]]></title>
    <link href="http://blebon.com/blog/2013/06/07/take-your-privacy-back/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-07T18:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blebon.com/blog/2013/06/07/take-your-privacy-back</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Do your part to resist Government surveillance and take back your privacy:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Browser Privacy: <a href="https://www.eff.org/https-everywhere">HTTPS Everywhere</a>, <a href="http://adblockplus.org/en/firefox">AdBlock Plus</a> + <a href="http://easylist.adblockplus.org/en/">EasyList</a>, <a href="https://www.disconnect.me/">Disconnect</a>, <a href="http://noscript.net/">NoScript</a> (FireFox), <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/notscripts/odjhifogjcknibkahlpidmdajjpkkcfn?hl=en">NotScript</a> (Chrome)</li>
<li>VPNs: <a href="https://www.privateinternetaccess.com/">Private Internet Access</a> (US), <a href="http://btguard.com/">BTGuard</a> (Canada), <a href="http://www.itshidden.eu/">ItsHidden</a> (Africa), <a href="https://ipredator.se/">Ipredator</a> (Sweden), <a href="http://faceless.me/">Faceless.me</a> (Cyprus / Netherlands)</li>
<li>Internet Anonymization: <a href="https://www.torproject.org/">Tor</a>, <a href="https://www.torproject.org/projects/torbrowser.html.en">Tor Browser Bundle</a>, <a href="http://i2p2.de/">I2P</a></li>
<li>Disk Encryption: <a href="http://www.truecrypt.org/">TrueCrypt</a> (Windows / OSX / Linux), <a href="http://support.apple.com/kb/ht4790">File Vault</a> (Mac).</li>
<li>File/Email Encryption: <a href="https://www.gpgtools.org/">GPGTools</a> + <a href="https://www.gpgtools.org/gpgmail/index.html">GPGMail</a> (Mac),  <a href="http://www.gpg4win.org/">GPG4Win</a> (Windows), <a href="http://www.enigmail.net/home/index.php">Enigmail</a> (Windows / OSX / Linux)</li>
<li>IM Encryption: <a href="http://www.pidgin.im/">Pidgin</a> + <a href="http://www.cypherpunks.ca/otr/">Pidgin OTR</a></li>
<li>IM/Voice Encryption: <a href="http://mumble.sourceforge.net/">Mumble</a>, <a href="https://jitsi.org/">Jitsi</a></li>
<li>Phone/SMS Encryption: <a href="http://www.whispersystems.org/">WhisperSystems</a>, <a href="https://guardianproject.info/apps/ostel/">Ostel</a>, <a href="https://myceli.al/projects/spore-android-client">Spore</a>, <a href="http://threema.ch/en/">Threema</a>, <a href="https://silentcircle.com/">Silent Circle</a> ($$$)</li>
<li>Google Alternative: <a href="https://duckduckgo.com/">DuckDuckGo</a>, <a href="https://startpage.com/">StartPage</a></li>
<li>Digital P2P Currency: <a href="http://bitcoin.org/">BitCoin</a></li>
<li>Live Anonymous/Secure Linux: <a href="https://tails.boum.org/">TAILS Linux</a></li>
</ul>


<p>If you have any problems installing or using the above software, please contact the projects. They would love to get feedback and help you use their software.</p>

<p>Have no clue what Cryptography is or why you should care? Checkout the
<a href="http://weise7.org/tmp/cryptobook-v1.1.pdf">Crypto Party Handbook</a>
or the <a href="https://ssd.eff.org/">EFF&rsquo;s Surveillance Self-Defense Project</a>.</p>

<p>Just want some simple tips? Checkout
<a href="https://www.eff.org/wp/effs-top-12-ways-protect-your-online-privacy">EFF&rsquo;s Top 12 Ways to Protect Your Online Privacy</a>.</p>

<hr />

<p>If you liked this comment, feel free to <a href="https://gist.github.com/postmodern/5018337">copy/paste it</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Facebook App Policy]]></title>
    <link href="http://blebon.com/blog/2013/04/28/facebook-app-policy/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-28T10:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blebon.com/blog/2013/04/28/facebook-app-policy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The data requested using the Mauritius Blog List application is used for the sole purpose of enhancing the user experience with the Mauritius Blog List app. Your data will not be used for marketing purposes and will not be used by the MBL when you disconnect from the app. However, the MBL has no control on what Facebook might be doing with your data.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why the 'Pacific' Protest Will Be a Flop]]></title>
    <link href="http://blebon.com/blog/2012/09/06/why-the-pacific-protest-will-be-a-flop/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-06T16:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blebon.com/blog/2012/09/06/why-the-pacific-protest-will-be-a-flop</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The media hype concerning the 9/11 &ndash; now moved to 9/10 &ndash; protest is unjustified. The ultimate outcome of all this nonsense will be a resounding failure, with a maximum of 3,000 youths expected &ndash; and I am in a generous mood today &ndash; and no opportunity for a concrete political movement in its aftermath. There are various signs pointing towards the failure of their endeavour:</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The movement itself has been inflated by the organisers who already had contacts within the local media. Thus, the inflated number of around 20,000 fans on Facebook is the direct result of the semi-celebrity status and media contacts of the organisers, and not a natural adhesion from 20 thousand angry youngsters. Any movement inflated either by money or celebrity is bound to deflate afterwards, and will be ephemeral.</p>

<p>It is easy to like a Facebook group in front of one&rsquo;s PC while sitting comfortably on a chair. Getting the numbers on Facebook is not so hard when you have the proper logistics and networking. However, what is really hard is to engage the fans into turning their &ldquo;likes&rdquo; into a concrete form of protest: marching on the streets on a Saturday afternoon. How many youngsters will choose to go to Port Louis instead of the revision sessions of private tuitions in the middle of the third term? How many Facebookers, who have been tired by a long working week, will really sacrifice a Saturday afternoon for an abstract cause?</p>

<p>Organising a protest march one day after the day dedicated to the Blessed Father Laval is a sign of political naivety and a disrespect to the sensibilities of the multi-cultural Mauritian community. This is the sort of mistake which tells you that the organisers do not have the proper knowledge and tact to handle a multi-cultural country. Alienating a sizeable section of the Mauritian community &ndash; the one which right now feels the more inclined to protest &ndash; by choosing a stage a protest march the day after 9/9 is a grave political mistake.</p>

<p>The laudable demands of the march are based on the assumption that the Mauritian Youth in general wants a country free of communalism and corruption: WRONG. The organisers would do well to attend one election campaign for the student unions of the UoM and UTM, and revise their expectations towards the Mauritian youngsters. In fact, I have seen enough to be convinced that equality and justice is a value truly cherished by a minority of idealist young people. Sadly, most Mauritian students nowadays are inclined to bend the rules or have resort to communalism if it suits their interests. Saken rod so bout!</p>

<p>The Mauritian people like to complain, but are not in urgent need of change. Most of them have enough to eat and enough drama to entertain themselves. They are truly well asleep with the bread and circuses provided by the three traditional parties, and the protest march will be yet another entertaining event, which will be long forgotten in a few weeks time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Fog Index]]></title>
    <link href="http://blebon.com/blog/2012/06/24/the-fog-index/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-24T16:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blebon.com/blog/2012/06/24/the-fog-index</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <strong>Fog Index</strong> is a rough measure that quantifies the readability of a written passage. The index was invented by an American called Robert Gunning. An index of around 7 is considered to be clear and precise. An index of 15 and above denotes a murky text that needs to be re-written.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The Fog Index is calculated as follows:</p>

<ol>
<li>Count the number of words in a section of the written work. This section should be at least 100 words long.</li>
<li>Count the number of complete thoughts in the sections. These thoughts are short sentences, or part of sentences that are separated by commas, colons or semicolons.</li>
<li>Divide the number of words by the number of thoughts. This number is the average thought length.</li>
<li>Count the number of words with three or more syllables in the section. Ignore proper names, compound names that are formed of simple words, and words which are three syllables because of the following suffixes: <em>-ed</em>, <em>-s</em>, and <em>-es</em>.</li>
<li>Calculate the percentage of multi-syllable words in the section.</li>
<li>Add this percentage to the average number of thoughts, and multiply the sum by 0.4 to obtain the Fog Index.</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[19]]></title>
    <link href="http://blebon.com/blog/2011/05/15/19/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-15T16:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blebon.com/blog/2011/05/15/19</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>During the 1993/1994 season, one lousy scouser infamously put the following words on a banner: &lsquo;Au revoir Cantona and Man United, come back when you&rsquo;ve won 18&rsquo;. He was refering to the scousers&#8217; 18 league titles compared with MUFC&rsquo;s (then) tally of 8. Little had that arrogant brat known how history would unfold in the following 17 years!</p>

<!--More-->


<p>14 May 2011. Fergie clinched United&rsquo;s 19th title &ndash; the 12th under his tenure &ndash; with arguably one of the weakest team to win the championish. While Liverpool are stuck to 18, United are one of the most consistent title winning sides in Europe and are still hungry for more. With the record as the team with most championships under the belt, the Reds can now confidently prepare for the clash of the titans at Wembley on May 24 against Barcelona, with Europe&rsquo;s most coveited trophy as the prize.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MBL Badges]]></title>
    <link href="http://blebon.com/blog/2011/03/28/mbl-badges/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-28T16:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blebon.com/blog/2011/03/28/mbl-badges</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can show your support for the <a href="http://mbl.blebon.com">Mauritius Blog List</a> by adding the following badges to your blog:</p>

<!--More-->


<p><strong>Logo:</strong><br/>
<img src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_DuhZ3DuqU3U/SmmxkMBazNI/AAAAAAAAAeM/ELHjGvUfJZY/s400/logo.png" alt="MBL Logo" /></p>

<pre><code>&lt;a href="http://mbl.blebon.com" target="_blank" title="All the Mauritian blogs under one page!"&gt;&lt;img alt="Mauritius Blog List" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_DuhZ3DuqU3U/SmmxkMBazNI/AAAAAAAAAeM/ELHjGvUfJZY/s400/logo.png" width="100%"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
</code></pre>

<p><strong>Badge:</strong><br/>
<img src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_DuhZ3DuqU3U/SmmybRrlexI/AAAAAAAAAe0/GHAWOtrgpls/s400/badge.png" alt="MBL Badge" /></p>

<pre><code>&lt;a href="http://mbl.blebon.com" target="_blank" title="All the Mauritian blogs under one page!"&gt;&lt;img alt="Mauritius Blog List" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_DuhZ3DuqU3U/SmmybRrlexI/AAAAAAAAAe0/GHAWOtrgpls/s400/badge.png"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate and Poverty]]></title>
    <link href="http://blebon.com/blog/2009/08/24/climate-and-poverty/"/>
    <updated>2009-08-24T18:16:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blebon.com/blog/2009/08/24/climate-and-poverty</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.iop.org/EJ/abstract/1748-9326/4/3/034004">A novel study has attempted to understand and predict the impact of climate change on the price of staple foods.</a> Ahmed <em>et al.</em> (2009) established that extreme climate events places huge pressure on the price of staple food; these staple foods are essential to poor households in developing countries and form a significant portion of their expenditure. The research provides an understanding of which countries and group are more vulnerable to poverty directly linked to extreme climate events.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Staple food, e.g. rice, wheat &hellip; is a significant source of the expenditure for a typical poor family living in a developing country. This large dependence is worrying since fluctuations in staple food price are bound to have a significant impact on poverty. This vulnerability of poor households to changing food prices motivates the need to understand the link between climate fluctuations, food prices and poverty.</p>

<p>Recent climate studies showed that hot, wet and dry extremes are becoming more and more frequent. There is direct evidence that such changes in climate patterns are already occurring. Crop damages resulting from this climate volatility will increase; the resulting reduction in crop production will put stress on food prices, which will shoot up.</p>

<p>The paper &lsquo;Climate volatility deepens poverty vulnerability in developing countries&rsquo; suggests that wage earners in urban areas are hit the hardest when the price of staple food goes up. This category is extremely exposed to food prices increase: since food form a large portion of their expenditure, rising prices push them below the poverty threshold for consumption. This is a worrying pattern since rural populations are expected to decrease by more than one third between 2010 and 2050. Rural food producers are less hardly hit by rising food prices; they are partially insulated from these effects since they benefit from the higher selling prices.</p>

<p>The report recommends sub-Saharan countries to invest in measures mitigating extreme climate effects, e.g. irrigation upgrading in Tanzania. These measures aim at increasing agricultural productivity, thereby buffering the impact of climate volatility. However the authors warn that these investments must also be accompanied by the removal of barriers to both credit and information.</p>

<p><strong>Reference:</strong><br/>
S.A. Ahmed, N.S. Diffenbaugh and T.W. Hertel, Climate volatility deepens poverty vulnerability in developing countries. <em>Environ. Res. Lett.</em> <strong>4</strong> (2009) 034004 (8p)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dangerous Homeopathy]]></title>
    <link href="http://blebon.com/blog/2009/08/21/dangerous-homeopathy/"/>
    <updated>2009-08-21T20:10:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blebon.com/blog/2009/08/21/dangerous-homeopathy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The World Health Organisation (WHO) has warned against the use of homeopathy for the treatment of HIV, TB, malaria, influenza and infant diarrhoea. Scientists and medics around the world have welcome WHO&rsquo;s clear position.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Early career scientists in the UK have previously appealed to the WHO to formally condemn the use of homeopathic treatment for these five serious diseases. This appeal aims at discouraging the use of inappropriate medication when people&rsquo;s lives are at risk. The WHO currently works in partnership with many organisations promoting homeopathy or alternative treatment in developing countries.</p>

<p>Homeopathy is presented as a safe, natural and long term treatment for various illnesses. The basis of homeopathy lies in the beliefs that:</p>

<ol>
<li>substances causing the same symptoms as the disease to be treated can effectively cure people, and</li>
<li>an over-diluted dose of the substance reduces its potential to harm and becomes very effective for healing.</li>
</ol>


<p>However, scientific investigations have not proven these claims, but rather show that homeopathy merely acts as a placebo.</p>

<p>Placebos (from the latin <em>I will please</em>) are inert prescriptions which can induce physiological changes. The belief that the patient is receiving treatment is what brings relief to him. However, the placebo effect simply alleviates the symptoms of the disease and is by no way a cure. Homeopathy cannot thus cure serious diseases, such as HIV, TB, malaria, flu and diarrhoea.</p>

<p>Promoting irrational and ineffective treatments for these serious illnesses can lead to catastrophic consequences. This has been demonstrated in South Africa, where Thabo Mbeki&rsquo;s reckless policy has led to an estimated 365,000 premature deaths. Advocating homeopathy for AIDS and flu in place of proper treatment is unethical, since homeopathy is no replacement for effective medication developed through rigorous clinical trials.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Problem of Life]]></title>
    <link href="http://blebon.com/blog/2009/07/21/the-problem-of-life/"/>
    <updated>2009-07-21T19:43:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blebon.com/blog/2009/07/21/the-problem-of-life</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am currently reading the latest issue of <a href="http://physicsworldarchive.iop.org/index.cfm?action=home">Physics World</a>. The current issues contains a series of captivating articles on the interface between physics and biology. One of them caught my attention: &ldquo;The quantum life&rdquo;.</p>

<!--more-->


<p><img src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_DuhZ3DuqU3U/SmYeaUF2h-I/AAAAAAAAAdM/Fxv4ZnhpiQE/s1600-h/Leavessnipedale.jpg" alt="Leaves" />
Life has always be problematic for us, physicists. Living organisms have long be regarded as magic entities, endowed with some obscure &lsquo;life force&rsquo;. Today, we know it&rsquo;s no magic at all; living cells are merely made up of ordinary matter which do extraordinary things. This ordinary matter obeys the laws of physics. But then, why does life has so many astonishing characteristics?</p>

<p>In the 1940s and 1950s, physicists hoped that quantum mechanics would evolve to a point that the mystery of life could be explained. The founders of the quantum theory, boosted by successful prediction of the behaviour of non-living matter at atomic level, hoped that quantum mechanics would be powerful enough to explain the behaviour of living matter. 50 years later, this dream is yet to be fulfilled.</p>

<p>One big question is the problematic origin of life, which proves to be a stubborn mystery. How could the simplest known living organism, which is still astonishingly complex, arise by assembly of inanimate matter? These questions are still open, and this is what makes biophysics so interesting.</p>

<p><strong>Reference:</strong><br/>
Davies, P., <em>The quantum life</em>. Physics World. Vol <strong>22</strong> No <strong>7</strong> July 2009, pp 24&mdash;28.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
